Seymour S. Cohen Papers 1938-1990 Mss.Ms.Coll.48
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by Others, 1940-1983; 15 boxes; 7 linear feet
  - "Experiments on Viral Growth in Cells Adapted to Sugars Feeding in to 6PG Path"--Notes, 1951-1952; Roth, L. (Box 39)
  - "Preparations of Phage, DNA; One Step Growth on Sugars of PG Path; Ghosts and Killing--Inconclusive"--Notes, 1951-1952; Roth, L. (Box 39)
  - "The Effect of Synthetic Prelyl-Alanyl-Theonine on the Reaggregation of Degraded TMV Protein", [196-]; Rudolph, Robert H. (Box 39)
  - "The Synthesis of Prelyl-Alanyl-Theonine", [196-]; Rudolph, Robert H. (Box 39)
  - -See Ser.V, "Molecular Weight of T4MV-RNA...", Schachman, Howard (Box 39)
  - "Activity of ara A on TAUAd; Prevention of ara A Lethality by 51 Cl Adenosine; Possible Synergism of ara A and ddA; Activity of ddAMP", 1973; Schwarz, Ruth (Box 39)
  - "Polymerization of TMV Protein in Presence of Synthetic Tripeptide Prolyl Alanyl Theonine", [1964]; Shalaby, Ragaa (Box 39)
  - [Lab Report], 1980; Shelness, Gregory (Box 39)
  - "Spermidine Biosynthesis in Chinese Cabbage", 1980; Shelness, Gregory (Box 39)
  - -See also Ser.V, "Early Studies--Before Protoplasts", Shelness, Gregory (Box 39)
  - -See Ser.III, "The Localization of Spermidine..." -See Ser.III, "Propylamine Transferases in the...", Sindhu, Ram K. (Box 39)
  - -See Ser.III, "Properties of Ultracentrifugally...", Stanley, Wendell M. (Box 39)
  - "Bacterial DNA After Thymineless Death; Ribosomes of Infected Cells"--Notes, 1961-1963; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 39)
  - "Conversion of Phage-Induced RNA to Deoxyribonucleotides in Extracts; Assay of dTMP Synthetase"--Notes, 1959-1960; 2 Folders; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein and Hazel Barner Leung (Box 39)
  - "Experiments on TAU, T-H-, T-..."--Notes, 1961-1962; 2 Folders; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Hydroxymethylase Synthase Assays"--Notebook, 1957-1958; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Metabolism of 51-Deoxythymidine by E. Coli", n.d.; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "mRNA in THU & TAU + Infection; DNA Stability After Alkali...", 1957-1964; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Phage Analyses, Tests of Auxotrophs, Utilization of HM-Dihydrosubstrates"--Notebook, 1955-1956; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Streptomycin"--Notes, 1959-1963; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Streptomycin on mRNA Formation..."--Notes, 1963-1964; 2 Folders; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 40)
  - "Test of Dihydro-, Hydroxymethyl in 15T-1B1Bu- + Phage; Non-Utilization of Nucleotides Drip of Nucleosides"--Notes, 1956-1959; Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 41)
  - -See also Ser.V, "Bacterial Extracts + Cations..." -See also Ser.V, "Mg++ vs. Polyamines...", Stern, Janet Lichtenstein (Box 41)
  - "K+ Depletion; tRNA with U* Incorporation; Mg Depletion...", 1970-1971; 3 Folders; Streibel, Ellen (Box 41)
  - "Polyamine Analyses; B697tRNA; K12 met-leu- Double Label Experiment..."--Notes, 1969-1970; 2 Folders; Streibel, Ellen (Box 41)
  - "Stocks; B45-met-; TAUst-TAUrel; CP78st vs. CP79rel"--Notes, 1968-1969; 2 Folders; Streibel, Ellen (Box 42)
  - -See Ser.IV, Kanazir, Dusan and S. Subotic. "A Conversion of Prolineless...", Subotic, S. (Box 42)
  - "Formation of Deoxyadenosine from Adenine by Nucleoside Phosphorylase", [1963]; Tarr, H.L.A. (Box 42)
  - "The Nucleic Acid Content of a Bacterial Virus", [1946]; Taylor, Alton R. (Box 42)
  - "Purification of Dihydrofolate Reductase", 1969; Teichberg, Saul (Box 42)
  - "Infected Plants; Uptake of [14c]-Methionine into Leaf Discs; Polyamines of Healthy and Infected Plants..."--Notes, 1975-1976; Torget, Robert William (Box 42)
- Series V. Research Notes, 1938-1980; 12 boxes; 5.5 linear feet
  Laboratory notes, graphs, charts, photographs, and a few test tubes (see "Protoplasts"). Experiments that were done with students are cross-referenced in Series IV. Many of the experiments are from the 1940s and 1950s. The earliest material is "Thromboplastin (Towards Dissertation)" dated 1938-1941. Subjects for the experiments include phosphogluconate, chloroplasts, protoplasts, ara, TAU, RNA polymerase, and polyamines. Photographs have been left in this series, and extensive conservation work needs to be done (see Conservation Note).
  - "Attempt to Sensitize TAU Ad to araAMP", 1970 (Box 43)
  - "Attempted Hydrolosis of NA by Diazomethane; Methylation of Nucleotides", 1956-1958 (Box 43)
  - "Bacterial Extracts + Cations; Effects of Streptomycin; DNFB Method of Estimating Polyamines; Isolation of Viral DNA with Protein from Extract", 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 43)
    -See also Ser.V, "Mg++ vs. Polyamines in..."
  - "Chemical Methods. ara A Nucleosides and Nucleotides; Animal Cell Culture; Bacterial Culture; Turnip Yellow Mosaic Virus; Chloroplasts", 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 44)
  - "Clotting Possibilities"--Notebook, 1940-1945 (Box 44)
  - "Cryptotethya, ara A & B96, Sponge Nucleic Acids and Nucleotides, Search for ara in M. Tuberculosis, Purine-Requiring Mutants, Electron Microscopy", 1960-1961, 1966 (Box 44)
  - "Cyanobacteria"--Notebook, 1973-1974 (Box 44)
  - "Distribution of G6P, 6PG Dehydrogenases Chaetopterus Enzymes", 1950-1951 (Box 44)
  - "DNAse of Lysates, Streptomycin Experiments, Some Analyses of Phage...", 1946-1947 (Box 44)
  - "Early Studies--Before Protoplasts", 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 44)
  - "Effects of Ethidium on TAUst, TAUxel; Bacterial Growth, Some Methods", 1972; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - "Experiments with O2 Electrode: RNA Viruses and Algae; Serum Oxidase and Polyamines; Functionality of Isolated Chloroplasts; Decline of Anacystis", 1974-1980 (Box 45)
  - "Glucose Media, Comparison of R+, R Viruses, Immunochemistry & Purification, Growth Curves, Turbidity, DNA and Protein Syntheses, Mutual Reactivation" (Box 45)
    - Folder #1, 1948-1950 (Box 45)
    - Folder #2, 1948-1950 (Box 45)
  - "Heparin Crystallization, Nucleophosphatase, TMV-RNA Size and Shape", Apr. 1941-Aug. 1942 (Box 45)
  - "Incorporation of Labeled araA and araAMP into L Cells", 1971; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - "Initial Observations (Kabacoff), Comparison of Glucose of r+ and r Strains", 1955-1957 (Box 46)
  - "Isolation and Characterization of Tobacco Necrosis Viruses", 1941-1942 (Box 46)
    -See also Ser.III, "Properties of Ultracentrifugally..."
  - "Isolation of HMC Nucleoside; Deamination of Pyrimidines and Nucleosides; DNAs-Resistant Core; DNA Synthesis in 15T-+T2; Preparation of HMU, Nucleoside", 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - "K+ Depletion, U* Incorporation, Isolation of tRNA, Polyamine Analyses", 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - "K12-Uronic Acids-Pentoses, Tests of Simultaneous Adaptation"--Notebook and Notes, Sep. 1947-Apr. 1948 (Box 46)
  - "L Cell Reserves; Lethality of Nucleosides and Nucleotides; DMSO Effects; Cloning" (Box 46)
    - Folder #1, 1970-1971 (Box 46)
    - Folder #2, 1970-1971 (Box 47)
  - "Lab Notes. Learning the Use of Warburg, Growth of E. Coli, Effect of Phage Membranes, Influenza Virus"--Notebook, 1945-1946 (Box 47)
  - "Laboratory Methods (Chemical Mainly); Some Pizer Studies (1960)", 1962 (Box 47)
  - "Laboratory Methods, Strains", 1950s-1970s; 2 folders (Box 47)
  - "Lethality of araA, araAMP to TAUAd; Effects of Methylioadenosine and Analogues on TAUAd", 1972; 2 folders (Box 47)
  - "Manometry: Cho Utilization", 1950-1952 (Box 48)
  - "Manometry of Cho Metabolism"--Notebook, 1951-1952 (Box 48)
  - "Mg++ vs. Polyamines in Aggregation of Ribosomal Subunits", 1958-1959 (Box 48)
    -See also Ser.V, "Bacterial Extracts + Cations..."
  - "Molecular Weight of T4MV-RNA; Sabbatical Leave with H. Schachman", 1955-1957 (Box 48)
  - "Ornithine Decarboxylase in E. Coli", 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 48)
  - "[14c]-Orotic Acid, [14c]-Serine Experiments", 1950-1953 (Box 48)
  - "Paper Chromatography"--Notebook, 1948 (Box 48)
  - "Perchloric Acid--Tryptophan Reaction", 1943-1944 (Box 48)
  - "Phage-Cho II, Nucleotides of r+ and r Strains, HMC Nucleotides- 0,1,2 Glucose", 1956-1958 (Box 48)
  - "Phosphogluconate, Gluconokinase...", 1950-1956; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - "Phosphogluconate Path Presumed Substrates, Products Properties (Liability, Reactions), Separation (Ion Exchange Paper), Analysis (Bacterial)", 1948-1949 (Box 49)
  - "Physical Studies: NA Fractions", n.d. (Box 49)
  - "Polyamines of Algae, of TYMV", 1977-1980 (Box 49)
  - "Preparation of araAMP, + 3H + 32P; Isolation of araA Nucleotides...", 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Protoplasts, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 50)
    contains test tubes
  - "Preparations of Phage for Base Analysis", 1949-1950 (Box 50)
  - "Rickettsial Fractions, Nucleohistone, Perchloric Acid-Tryptophan, Proteus OX-19"--Notebook, 1944-1945 (Box 50)
  - "RNA Polymerase; Media-Putrescine Mutant...", 1968-1970 (Box 50)
  - "Schramm Synthesis of ara A; Fletcher Synthesis of ara A; Analyses of Cryptotethya", 1962-1963 (Box 50)
  - "Search for Phosphoarabino Mutase Isomerase", 1961-1962 (Box 50)
  - "Sedimentation of Extracts; Effects of Mg++, Spermidine", 1958-1959 (Box 51)
  - "Spectra: Cho, Pyrimidines and Purines, Other", 1948-1957 (Box 51)
  - "Streptomycin Nucleate Precipitation, Lysis from Without in Anaerobiosis...", 1946 (Box 51)
  - "Studies in Typhus Vaccine", 1942-1946; 2 folders (Box 51)
  - "Studies with B. Proteus OX-19 Chemical Modifications", 1944-1945 (Box 51)
  - "Syntheses, Labeled Nucleotides. araA (r) araAMP (r) araATP", 1970-1971 (Box 51)
  - "Synthesis of ara (A,C); Synthesis with Polyphosphoric Acid", 1964-1966 (Box 52)
  - "TAU-ST - TAU-REL (Letter of Origin); Isolation by Gutcho Method; Isolation from L Cells...", 1968-1969 (Box 52)
  - "TAU Stringent vs. TAU Relaxed", 1966; 2 folders (Box 52)
  - "Tests of Dansyl Method; Polyamines in Nucleates" (Box 52)
    - Folder #1-2, 1968-1969 (Box 52)
    - Folder #3, 1968-1969 (Box 53)
  - "Tetrahydrouridine Effects; Infections; TAU st, TAU rel", 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 53)
  - "Thromboplastin (Toward Dissertation)--Notebook, 1938-1941 (Box 53)
  - "tRNA Studies. Binding of Spermidine Ethidium...", 1970-1974 (Box 53)
    -See also Ser.III, "The Binding of Polyamines and Ethidium to tRNA"
  - "TYMV Chloroplasts; Attempted Infection of Bacteria, Bluegreens with Viral RNA; Polyamines in MET Bacteria", 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Unidentified, 1956-1957 (Box 54)
  - "Uronic Acids, Pentoses: Bacterial Growth and Metabolism", Fall 1947-Spring 1948 (Box 54)
  - "Warburg Experiments, Phage, Pentose", 1945-1946 (Box 54)
  - "Warburg Manometry; Respiration, Fermentation, RQ; Growth, Infection; [1-14c]-Gluconokinase, Pentose Kinase"--Notebook, 1946-1971 (Box 54)
- Series VI. Photographs, 1941-1983; 1 box; 0.25 linear feet
  Photographs of Cohen in his laboratory, at conferences, at the Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts, and with Alfred D. Hershey. Also included are photographs of Cohen's students and photographs of experiments results (e.g., of chloroplasts).
  - American Association for Cancer Research. Board of Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 55)
  - B. Megaterium, 10 Jun. 1964 (Box 55)
  - Chloroplast, 29 Mar. 1974 (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., [1950] (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., 1963 (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., 1963-1971? (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., 1971-1976? (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S., 1982 (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S. (Box 55)
    -See also Ser.VI, American Association for Cancer Research. Board of Directors
    -See also Ser.VI, Gordan Research Conference
    -See also Ser.VI, International Symposium on Polyamines in Normals and Neoplastic Cells
    -See also Ser.VI, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
    -See also Ser.VI, Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts
  - Cohen, Seymour S.--University of Colorado Identification Card, n.d. (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S. and Alfred D. Hershey, 1946 or 1947 (Box 55)
  - Cohen, Seymour S. and Tungsen Xu, [198-] (Box 55)
  - Gordan Research Conference, 7-11 Jul. 1980 (Box 55)
  - Hershey, Alfred D. (Box 55)
    -See Ser.VI, Cohen, Seymour S. and Alfred D. Hershey
  - Hirudonine, [1981] (Box 55)
  - International Symposium on Polyamines in Normals and Neoplastic Cells, 8-10 Sep. 1980 (Box 55)
  - "Minor Bases Found in a Variety of RNA Samples", [1973] (Box 55)
  - "Molecular Weight of T4MV-RNA; Sabbatical Leave with H. Schachman", 1955-1957 (Box 55)
  - Phage (øe), [1976] (Box 55)
  - "Properties of Ultracentrifugally Isolated Viruses Causing Tobacco Necrosis", [ca. 1941] (Box 55)
  - Raina, Aarne (Family), 31 May 1979 (Box 55)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1942 (Box 55)
  - Saint Jude Children's Research Hospital, Nov. 1973 (Box 55)
  - "Sedimentation of Extracts; Effects of Mg++, Spermidine", 1958-1959 (Box 55)
  - Sekiguchi, Mutsuo (Family), [1961] (Box 55)
  - Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts, 21 Sep. 1973 (Box 55)
  - "Studies on Typhus Vaccine", 1942-1946 (Box 55)
  - Xu, Tungsen (Box 55)
    -See Ser.VI, Cohen, Seymour S. and Tungsen Xu
  - Yamanoha, Banri (Family), [1983] (Box 55)